<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!--
  ~  Copyright (c) 2009, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
  ~
  ~  WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
  ~  Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
  ~  in compliance with the License.
  ~  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  ~  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  ~  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  ~  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  ~  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  ~  under the License.
  -->

<!DOCTYPE html
        PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en">
    <head>
        <meta content="text/html; charset=iso-8859-1" http-equiv="content-type"/>
        <title>WSO2 API Manager v1.0.0-M6 Released - 30th May 2012</title>
    </head>
    <body>
        <div id="main-content">
            <h1>The WSO2 API Manager 1.0.0-M6 Released!</h1>

            <p>
                The WSO2 API Manager team is pleased to announce the release of version 1.0.0-M6 of
                the Open Source API Manager.
            </p>

            <p>
                WSO2 API Manager is a platform for creating, managing, consuming and monitoring
                APIs. It employs proven SOA best practices to solve a wide range of API
                management challenges such as API provisioning, API governance, API security
                and API monitoring. It combines some of the most powerful and mature components
                of the WSO2's state-of-the-art Carbon platform to deliver a smooth and end-to-end
                API management experience while catering to both API publisher and API consumer
                requirements.
            </p>
            
            <p>
                WSO2 API Manager is comprised of several modules.
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li><b>API provider:</b> Define new APIs and manage them</li>
                <li><b>API store:</b> Browse published APIs and subscribe to them</li>
                <li><b>API gateway:</b> The underlying API runtime based on WSO2 ESB</li>
            </ul>

            <p>
                WSO2 API Manager is developed on top of the revolutionary
                <a href="http://wso2.org/projects/carbon">WSO2 Carbon platform</a>
                (Middleware a' la carte),
                an OSGi based framework that provides seamless modularity to your SOA via
                componentization. This release also contains many new features and a range of
                optional components (add-ons) that can be installed to customize the behavior 
                of the API Manager. Further, any existing features of the product which are not 
                required in your environment can be easily removed using the underlying 
                provisioning framework of Carbon. In brief, WSO2 API Manager can be fully 
                customized and tailored to meet your exact API management needs.
            </p>            

            <h2>How to Run</h2>
            <ol>
                <li>Extract the downloaded zip</li>
                <li>Go to the bin directory in the extracted folder</li>
                <li>Run the wso2server.sh or wso2server.bat as appropriate</li>
                <li>Launch a web browser and navigate to http://localhost:9763/apiprovider
                    to access the API provider webapp
                </li>
                <li>Navigate to http://localhost:9763/apistore to access the API store</li>                
                <li>Use "admin", "admin" as the username and password to login as an admin</li>
                <li>If you need to start the OSGi console with the server use the property
                    -DosgiConsole when starting the server. The INSTALL.txt file found on the
                    installation directory will give you a comprehensive set of options and
                    properties that can be passed into the startup script
                </li>                
            </ol>

            <h2>New Features of WSO2 API Manager 1.0.0-M6</h2>
            <p>
                This release of API Manager comes with a horde of new features and bug fixes.
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li><a href="https://wso2.org/jira/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10230&amp;version=10564">List of resolved issues</a></li>
            </ul>

            <h2>Key Features of WSO2 API Manager</h2>
            <p>
                Following is a categorization of the core features supported by WSO2 API Manager
                based on the target user group.
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    API Publisher:
                    <ul>
                        <li>Publish APIs to external consumers and partners, as well as internal
                        users; SOAP and REST services are supported</li>
                        <li>Manage API versions (several versions can be deployed in parallel)</li>
                        <li>Govern the API lifecycle (publish, deprecate, retire)</li>
                        <li>Attach documentation (files, external URLs) to APIs</li>
                        <li>Apply Security policies to APIs (authentication, authorization)</li>
                        <li>Attach SLAs</li>
                        <li>Provision and Manage API keys</li>
                        <li>Track consumers per API</li>
                        <li>Monitor API usage and performance, SLA compliance</li>
                        <li>Gather consumers requirements</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>
                    API Consumers:
                    <ul>
                        <li>Find useful APIs by browsing or searching through the API Store: view 
                        top rated, top used and featured APIs</li>
                        <li>Explore API documentation and ask questions to publisher</li>
                        <li>Register applications and obtain API keys</li>
                        <li>Subscribe to API changes and receive news</li>
                        <li>Evaluate APIs, rate APIs, and share comments</li>
                        <li>Request features and improvements from publishers</li>
                        <li>Participate in online forums</li>
                        <li>OAuth2 support for API access</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>

            <h2>Known Issues</h2>
            <p>
                All the open issues pertaining to WSO2 API Manager are reported at the following
                location:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <a href="https://wso2.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?requestId=10682">
                        WSO2 API Manager open issues
                    </a>
                </li>
            </ul>

            <h2>How You Can Contribute</h2>
            <h3>
                Mailing Lists
            </h3>
            <p>
                Join our mailing list and correspond with the developers directly.
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Developer List :
                    <a href="mailto:dev@wso2.org">dev@wso2.org</a>
                    |
                    <a href="mailto:dev-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">Subscribe</a>
                    |
                    <a href="http://wso2.org/mailarchive/dev/">Mail Archive</a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    User List :
                    <a href="mailto:user@wso2.org">user@wso2.org</a>
                    |
                    <a href="mailto:user-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">Subscribe</a>
                    |
                    <a href="http://wso2.org/mailarchive/user/">Mail Archive</a>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <h3>
                Reporting Issues
            </h3>
            <p>
                We encourage you to report issues, documentation faults and feature requests
                regarding
                WSO2 API Manager through the public<a href="http://www.wso2.org/jira/browse/APISTORE">API Manager
                JIRA</a>. You
                can use the
                <a href="http://www.wso2.org/jira/browse/CARBON">Carbon JIRA</a>
                to report any
                issues related to the Carbon base framework or associated Carbon components.
            </p>

            <h2>Support</h2>
            <p>
                We are committed to ensuring that your enterprise middleware deployment is
                completely supported from evaluation to production. Our unique approach
                ensures that all support leverages our open development methodology and is
                provided by the very same engineers who build the technology.
            </p>
            <p>
                For more details and to take advantage of this unique opportunity please
                visit<a href="http://wso2.com/support">http://wso2.com/support</a>.
            </p>
            <p>
                For more information about WSO2 API Manager please see<a
                    href="http://wso2.com/products/api-manager/">
                http://wso2.com/products/api-manager/</a>.
            </p>


            <p>
                <i>-- The WSO2 API Manager Team --</i>
            </p>
        </div>
    </body>
</html>
