<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!--
 ~ Copyright (c) WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
 ~
 ~ WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
 ~ Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
 ~ in compliance with the License.
 ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
 ~
 ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 ~
 ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
 ~ software distributed under the License is distributed on an
 ~ "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
 ~ KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
 ~ specific language governing permissions and limitations
 ~ under the License.
 -->
<!DOCTYPE html
        PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en">
    <head>
        <title>@product.name@ - Managing a Human Task Instance - TODO - </title>
        <link href="../css/bps-docs.css" rel="stylesheet"/>
        <link href="styles/dist-docs.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all"/>
    </head>
    <body>
        <h1>Managing a Human Task Instance - TODO</h1>


        <h3>Table of Content</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="#Task-Listing">Task Listing</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Task-View">Task Details View</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Task-Privileges">Task Privileges</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Task-Life-Cycle">Task Life Cycle</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Task-Event-History">Task Event History</a></li>
        </ul>

        <h2 id="Task-Listing">Task Listing</h2>

        <p>
            Once you log in the the WSO2 BPS the list of tasks could be viewed by clicking on the Task List link on the manage menu.

        </p>

        <p><img src="../images/humantask-task-lc/view_task_list_link.png" alt="Task Listing"/></p>

        <p>
            The task list page would show you the available tasks.
        </p>

        <p><img src="../images/humantask-task-lc/task_list_my_tasks.png" alt="Task Listing"/></p>

        <p>
            The following basic filtering options are present in the task list page.
        </p>

        <ul>
            <li>
                <b>My Tasks</b>

                <p>
                    The list of tasks currently assigned to you and are in progress
                </p>

            </li>

            <li>
                <b>Claimable</b>

                <p>
                    The claimable tasks are the list of tasks which the user can claim and reserve. Any tasks would
                    become claimable for a particular user if he has the role of <b>Potential Owners</b> of the task definition.
                </p>

            </li>

            <li>
                <b>Admin Tasks</b>

                <p>
                    A list of tasks which the current logged in user have the administration rights.
                    The user can perform the administration actions like reassignment on these tasks.
                </p>

            </li>

            <li>
                <b>Notifications</b>

                <p>
                    A list of notifications which are accessible to the current logged in user.
                </p>

            </li>

            <li>
                <b>All Tasks</b>

                <p>
                    A list of all tasks that the logged in user can view. This would also include all the
                    tasks which are already completed.
                </p>

            </li>


        </ul>

        <h2 id="Task-View">Task Details View</h2>

        <p>
            The task details could be viewed when you click on the particular task id on the task list page. The task view would depend
            on the current status of the task and the particular user's privileges on that task.
        </p>

        <p><img src="../images/humantask-task-lc/task_view.png" alt="Task Details View"/></p>

        <h2 id="Task-Privileges">Task Privileges</h2>

        <p>
            The actions a particular user can perform on a task would depend on the privileges
            granted to that user and the current status of the task. These privileges will be based
            on the logical people group the user belongs to. For an example only the <b>Actual Owner</b>
            of the task would be able to release a task already assigned to him.
        </p>


        <h2 id="Task-Life-Cycle">Task Life Cycle</h2>

        <p>The following transition diagram shows how the task propagates from each stated based on the
            action performed.
        </p>



        <p><img src="../images/humantask-task-lc/task_lc.gif" alt="Task Life Cycle"/></p>

        <p>
            The following table lists some important task actions along with the authorised
            logical people groups and the pre and post state transition of the task.
        </p>

        <table id="Task-Actions-Table">
            <tbody>
                <tr>
                    <th>Action</th>
                    <th>Description</th>
                    <th>Authorised Roles</th>
                    <th>Pre-State(s)</th>
                    <th>Post-State</th>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Claim</td>
                    <td>Claim responsibility for a task, i.e. set the task to status Reserved </td>
                    <td>Potential Owners</td>
                    <td>Ready</td>
                    <td>Reserved</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Start</td>
                    <td>Start the execution of the task </td>
                    <td>Actual Owner <br/>Potential Owners</td>
                    <td>Ready <br/>Reserved</td>
                    <td>InProgress</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Stop</td>
                    <td>Cancel/stop the processing of the task. The task returns to the Reserved state. </td>
                    <td>Actual Owner</td>
                    <td>InProgress</td>
                    <td>Reserved</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Suspend</td>
                    <td>Suspend the task </td>
                    <td>Task Stakeholders <br/> Business Administrator</td>
                    <td>Ready<br/>Reserved<br/>InProgress</td>
                    <td>Suspended</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Resume</td>
                    <td>Resume a suspended task. </td>
                    <td>Task Stakeholders <br/> Business Administrator</td>
                    <td>Ready<br/>Reserved<br/>InProgress</td>
                    <td>Suspended</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Skip</td>
                    <td>Skips the task</td>
                    <td>Task Initiator<br/>Task Stakeholders<br/>Business Administrator</td>
                    <td>Suspended</td>
                    <td>Ready<br/>Reserved<br/>InProgress</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Release</td>
                    <td>Release the task, i.e. set the task back to status Ready.</td>
                    <td>Actual Owner</td>
                    <td>InProgress<br/>Reserved</td>
                    <td>Ready</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Fail</td>
                    <td>Execution of the task fails.</td>
                    <td>Actual Owner</td>
                    <td>InProgress</td>
                    <td>Failed</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Add Comment </td>
                    <td>Add a comment to a task. </td>
                    <td>Task Stakeholders<br/>Potential Owners<br/>Actual Owner<br/>Business Administrator</td>
                    <td>(any state)</td>
                    <td>(no state transition)</td>
                </tr>
            </tbody>
        </table>

        <h4>Basic Flow of a Task</h4>

        <ul>
            <li><b>Claiming a Task</b>

                <p>
                    When a task is created it would be in <b>Ready</b> state. Ready state means that the task
                    is ready to be claimed by a user in the <b>Potential Owner</b> logical people group. A user
                    having the Potential Owner role can claim the task by clicking on the <b>Claim</b> button
                    in the task details page. When a user claims the task the, it would go to the <b>Reserved</b> state
                    which means that the task is now owned by the user who claimed the particular task.
                </p>

            </li>

            <li><b>Starting a Task</b>

                <p>
                    A task could be started by either of the following logical people groups. First group being
                    the <b>Actual Owner</b> group which has already claimed the task. Otherwise <b>Potential Owner</b>s
                    can directly start a task which would automatically be claimed to the user starting the task. Once a task is started
                    you would see the input form rendered to capture the task output. The output form
                    would depend on the output form uploaded with the task definition. Refer the image below for a
                    sample output form rendering.
                </p>
                <p><img src="../images/humantask-task-lc/task_after_starting.png" alt="Task Response"/></p>
            </li>

            <li><b>Completing a Task</b>

                <p>
                    The task completion happens with the task owner performs the completion action provided with the
                    output rendering form.
                </p>
                <p><img src="../images/humantask-task-lc/task_completion.png" alt="Task Completion"/></p>

                <p>
                    Once the task is completed, the particular task would be moved out from the
                    <b>My Tasks</b> list of the particular user.
                </p>
            </li>

            <li><b>Other Actions</b>

            Refer the list of actions in <a href="#Task-Actions-Table">Task Actions Table</a>

            </li>

        </ul>

        <h2 id="Task-Event-History">Task Event History</h2>

        <p>
            Users can view the events occurred on a particular task by clicking on the <b>History</b> tab
            of the task details page. The task history details would contain information about the
            action, user who performed that operation, time stamp of the event and any state transitions
            due to the event. Refer the below image for a sample list of events.
        </p>

        <p><img src="../images/humantask-task-lc/task_history.png" alt="Task Event History"/></p>


    </body>


</html>
