<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!--
  ~  Copyright (c) 2009, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
  ~
  ~  WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
  ~  Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
  ~  in compliance with the License.
  ~  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  ~  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  ~  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  ~  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  ~  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  ~  under the License.
  -->

<!DOCTYPE html
     PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"
     "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en">
  <head>
      <meta content="text/html; charset=iso-8859-1" http-equiv="content-type"/>
      <title>WSO2 CSG v1.0.0-alpha release</title>
  </head>
  <body>
  <div id="header">
</div>

<div id="main-content">
<h1>The WSO2 Cloud Services Gateway (CSG) 1.0.0-alpha release</h1>

<p>
    The WSO2 CSG team is pleased to announce the release of version 1.0.0-alpha of
    the Cloud Services Gateway(CSG).
</p>

<p>
    WSO2 Cloud Services Gateway(or CSG for short) is a framework that can be used to
    expose a private service that is behind a firewall to the outside world in a
    secure manner. The framework consists of CSG server and the CSG Agent component.
    CSG Agent component should be installed in a service hosting product( such as
    WSO2 Application Server).
</p>

<p>
    WSO2 CSG 1.0.0-alpha is developed on top of the revolutionary
    <a href="http://wso2.org/projects/carbon">WSO2 Carbon platform</a>,
    an OSGi based framework that provides seamless modularity to your SOA via
    componentization.</p>

<p>
    You can download this distribution from <a href="http://dist.wso2.org/downloads/csg">
    http://wso2.org/downloads/csg</a> and give it a try.</p>

<h2>How to Run </h2>
<ol>
  <li>Extract the downloaded zip</li>
  <li>Go to the bin directory in the extracted folder</li>
  <li>Run the wso2server.sh or wso2server.bat as appropriate</li>
  <li>If you need to start the OSGi console with the server use the property
    -DosgiConsole when starting the server. The INSTALL.txt file found on the
    installation directory will give you a comprehensive set of options and
    properties that can be passed into the startup script</li>
  <li>To publish a service, login to a service hosting product which has the CSG Agent installed</li>
  </ol>

<h2>Key Features of WSO2 CSG</h2>
<ul>
    <li>Ability to expose a private SOAP service securely and configurable manner</li>
    <li>Ability to expose a private REST service securely and configurable manner</li>
    <li>Ability to expose a private JSON service securely and configurable manner</li>
    <li>Multi-tenancy support(Ability to expose a private service with same name by two different
    tenants)</li>
    <li>Ability to configure dead messages clean up task</li>
</ul>

<h2>Known Issues</h2>
<p>
    All the open issues pertaining to WSO2 CSG 1.0.0-alpha are reported at following
    locations:
</p>

<ul>
    <li>
        <a href="https://wso2.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?mode=hide&amp;requestId=10664">
            Open CSG issues
        </a>
    </li>
    <li><a href="https://wso2.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?requestId=10524">
        Underling routing engine issues</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://wso2.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?requestId=10525">
        Base framework issues</a></li>
</ul>

    <h2>Release 1.0.0-alpha</h2>
    <p>This release contains a number of bug fixes.</p>
    <p>ChangeLog</p>
    <ol>
        <li>CARBON-12603 - Added a 'What's this ?' help button which gives more information about
            CSG server URL.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12630 - CSG Agent should not allow users to delete a server when there are services
            published onto it.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12607 - Added a link to the tool section for the EPRs of the CSG service.</li>
        <li>CARBON-11771 - Added registry transaction into places where registry API is used.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12404 - Now no custom mediators can be deployed on CSG. This will avoid someone stealing
            the messages in the thrift buffers</li>
        <li>CARBON-12485 - Removed the unwanted features such as VFS, JMS etc..</li>
        <li>CARBON-12604 - Fixed the CSG server to have a default user, 'csguser'.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12577 - Fixed the CSG user guide.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12872 - Added integration tests for CSG.</li>
        <li>CARBON-11779 - Added the proxy WSDL into registry.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12782 - Updated the documentation to include information about the 'csguser'.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12940 - Added all csg.properties into an appendix.</li>
        <li>CARBON-13027 - Fixed issue when clicking Registry browser.</li>
        <li>CARBON-13028 - Source packs for CSG products and CSG service.</li>
    </ol>

    <h2>Release 1.0.0-alpha RC3</h2>
    <p>This release contains a number of bug fixes and documentation for the CSG product.</p>
    <p>ChangeLog</p>
    <ol>
        <li>CARBON-12428 - Proxy is now created with the back end WSDL.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12421 - License file is fixed.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12422 - Updated README.txt to match with INSTALL.txt.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12417 - Display a warning for Try it and WSDL tools if the remote CSG server is down.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12426 - Added a mechanism to re-deploy the CSG service if remote server dies.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12483 - Fixed not to assume localhost for thrift client always.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12416 - Fixed the CSG product theme and logo.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12476 - Fixed the polling task to shutdown properly.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12477 - Fixed RESTful service publishing</li>
    </ol>

    <h2>Release 1.0.0-alpha RC2</h2>
    <p>This release provides the CSG Stratos service.</p>
    <p>ChangeLog</p>
    <ol>
        <li>CARBON-12352 - Back end errors/exception has not transferred to front end properly.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12353 - Do not suspend the public CSG proxy endpoint in any case.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12357 - Enable CSG transport sender dynamically in Stratos environment.</li>
        <li>CARBON-12369 - Increase Thrift client time out to suite a Stratos deployment. </li>
    </ol>

    <h2>Release 1.0.0-alpha RC1</h2>
    <p>This is the first public availability of WSO2 Cloud Services Gateway</p>

<h2>How You Can Contribute</h2>
    <h3>
      Mailing Lists
    </h3>
    <p>
      Join our mailing list and correspond with the developers directly.
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        Developer List : <a href="mailto:carbon-dev@wso2.org">carbon-dev@wso2.org</a>
        | <a href="mailto:carbon-dev-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">Subscribe</a>
        | <a href="http://wso2.org/mailarchive/carbon-dev/">Mail Archive</a>
      </li>
     </ul>
    <h3>
      Reporting Issues
    </h3>
    <p>
      We encourage you to report issues, documentation faults and feature requests regarding
      WSO2 CSG or in the Carbon base framework through the public
      <a href="http://www.wso2.org/jira/browse/CARBON">Carbon JIRA</a>.
    </p>
<h2>Support</h2>
<p>
    We are committed to ensuring that your enterprise middleware deployment is
    completely supported from evaluation to production. Our unique approach
    ensures that all support leverages our open development methodology and is
    provided by the very same engineers who build the technology.
</p>
<p>
    For more details and to take advantage of this unique opportunity please
    visit <a href="http://wso2.com/support">http://wso2.com/support</a>.
</p>

<p><i>-- The WSO2 CSG Team --</i> </p>
</div>
  </body>
</html>
