<!--
~ Copyright 2005-2008 WSO2, Inc. (http://wso2.com)
~
~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
~
~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
~
~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
~ limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

    <body>
	<p>[<a href="http://wso2.org/downloads/gadget-server">Download</a>]
            | [<a href="index_docs.html">Documentation Home</a>] | [<a href="release_notes.html">Release Note</a>]
        </p>

        <div id="main-content">
            <h1>Welcome to the WSO2 Gadget Server 1.4.0</h1>
            <p>This document provides an
                introduction to the concepts and use of the Gadget Server, and will help you
                get started using Web service technology.
            </p>

            <p>Services
are the building blocks of SOAs. A complete SOA platform needs to
enable the creation of services on a wide variety of platforms, to
support today's heterogeneous enterprises. However, end users mostly
care about their business needs and they will demand complete access to
every application and service required to satisfy these needs.
Organisations need to come up with tangible applications that help
utilise existing investments made in building their SOAs, irrelevant of
the underlying technology (Java, .Net, PHP or any other) while
maintaining a people centric approach and delivering maximum value for
the business user.<br />
<br />
The WSO2 Gadget Server is a light weight portal platform enabling the
re-purposing and unification of existing services in an organisation's
SOA.<br />
<br />
Gadgets deployed in WSO2 Gadget Server are HTML and Javascript wrapped
in XML adhering to the Google Gadgets Specification and thus can be
hosted anywhere. This increases scalability and allows organisations to
leverage existing services and code to satisfy new user requirements.
Gadgets are self contained, ready to use applications which are task
specific and lightweight. The WSO2 Gadget Server powers the rendering
and management of gadgets according to the preference of the business
user via a drag and drop layout of gadgets, per gadget settings and
different tabs for gadget categorization among others.<br />
<br />
The WSO2 Gadget Server also provides an Enterprise Gadget Repository
from where business users can pick and choose additional, recommended
gadgets to be added to their individual portal pages. This repository
helps enterprises govern the gadgets exposed to the end user while the
users get to rate and comment on each gadget found in the repository.<br />
<br />
The WSO2 Gadget Server is released under the Apache License v2.0<br />
</p>


            <h3>features in the 1.4.0 release:<br />
</h3>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Enterprise class Portal interface</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>Users get to organise gadgets in a familiar portal interface.
Sets of gadgets can be organised using tabs. Individual gadgets can be
moved between tabs as well as cloning an entire tab to be used as the
foundation for a new tab.<br />
  </dd>
</dl>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Client Side Gadgets</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>Any gadget adhering to the Google Gadget Specification can be
added to the portal. These gadgets are basically HTML and Javascript
embedded in XML. They can be hosted in any publicly accessible Web
Server. The URL of the gadget XML is used to add them to the Portal.<br />
  </dd>
</dl>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Enterprise Gadget Repository</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>Organisations can maintain a central repository of gadgets.
Portal users can browse and add gadgets from this repository to their
individual portals, while rating and commenting on individual gadgets.<br />
  </dd>
</dl>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Anonymous Mode</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>Users can experience most of the Portal's functionality
'excluding' the gadget Repository even before registration and sign in.
All data in this mode will be stored in the user's browser.<br />
  </dd>
</dl>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Multi option user registration and sign in</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>User registration and sign in can be done using OpenID or
Infocards in addition to the traditional user name and password based
scheme.<br />
  </dd>
</dl>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Management Console</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>Helps configure and manage the server, its users and the
Enterprise Gadget Repository via an intuitive browser based
administrative interface.</dd>
</dl>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Custom Layouts for Tabs</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>Gadget Server users can choose a desired layout form
six different layouts when creating a new tab.</dd>
</dl>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Role Based Permissions</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>Gadgets can be restricted based on users role.</dd>
</dl>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Make SOAP Request Support</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>Not only REST style requests, gadgets written for
WSO2 Gadget Server can consume SOAP only web service
via make SOAP Request.</dd>
</dl>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Theming Support</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>Gadget Server users can create custom templates
for the portal UI, and add them via Gadget Server
management console.</dd>
</dl>
<ul style="font-style: italic;">
  <li>Gadget Archive Deployment</li>
</ul>
<dl>
  <dd>With WSO2 Carbon Application deployment, users can,
write gadgets using Carbon Studio and deploy the
gadget archive in to the Gadget server.</dd>
</dl>
<br />

                <p>
                    Please refer the
                    <a href="release_notes.html">Gadget Server 1.4.0 Release Note</a>
                    for more details.<br />
<br />

                </p>
            <h2>Mailling Lists</h2>
            <p>Your feedback on WSO2 Gadget Server is most appreciated. Please send them to our user mailing lists.</p> 
            <ul>
              <li>WSO2 Gadget Server Users' mailing list: <a href="mailto:gs-user@wso2.org%20">gs-user@wso2.org </a> | <a href="mailto:gs-user-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">Subscribe</a>
                | <a href="mailto:gs-user-request@lists.wso2.com?subject=unsubscribe">Unsubscribe</a>
                | <a href="http://www.wso2.org/mailarchive/gs-user/">Mail
                Archive</a></li><br />
  <br />

            </ul>

            
        </div>
    </body>
</html>
