<!--
  ~  Copyright (c) 2005-2010, WSO2 Inc. (http://wso2.com) All Rights Reserved.
  ~
  ~  WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
  ~  Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
  ~  in compliance with the License.
  ~  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  ~  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  ~  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  ~  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  ~  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  ~  under the License.
  -->
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <head>
        <link media="all" type="text/css" rel="stylesheet" href="css/mashup-docs.css"/>
        <link media="all" href="css/SyntaxHighlighter.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css"/>
        <script src="js/shCore.js" language="javascript"/>
        <script src="js/shBrushJScript.js" language="javascript"/>
        <script src="js/shBrushJava.js" language="javascript"/>
        <script src="js/shBrushSql.js" language="javascript"/>
        <script src="js/shBrushXml.js" language="javascript"/>
    </head>
    <body style="direction: ltr;">
        <p>[<a href="http://wso2.org/downloads/gadget-server">Download</a>]
            | [<a href="index_docs.html">Documentation Home</a>] | [<a href="release_notes.html">
                Release
                Note</a>]
        </p>
        <div id="main-content">
            <h1>The WSO2 Gadget Server 1.4.0 Released!</h1>

            <p>The WSO2 Gadget Server team is pleased to announce the release of version 1.4.0 of
                the WSO2 Gadget Server
            </p>

            <p>The WSO2 Gadget Server is an enterprise grade portal, which is available under the <a
                    href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0.html">Apache
                Software License v2.0</a>. With the WSO2 Gadget Server, you can offer your execs,
                employees,
                partners, or customers a way to get all the information in one place that they need.
                Each user's
                dashboard is individualized, allowing him/her to add, customize, and rearrange
                gadgets, as well
                as group them into tab sets. The open "Web" model means users can select gadgets not
                only from
                your enterprise, but also from Google and many others.
            </p>

            <p>Google Gadget development is an easy, standards-based process - any Web developer
                with basic skills in HTML, Javascript, and XML can develop and deploy a custom
                gadget. These gadgets can be hosted at any URL, or stored and advertised within the
                Gadget Server's Gadget Repository.

                Accessing enterprise Web services through a gadget is easy, reliable, and secure.
                And the WSO2 platform provides many options for connecting with diverse data
                sources-from the WSO2 Data Services Server connecting to data bases and spreadsheets
                to the WSO2 Mashup Server connecting and collating data from multiple sources (which
                might include external cloud services and even Web pages).
            </p>

            <p>You can download this distribution from
                <a
                        href="http://wso2.org/downloads/gadget-server">
                    http://wso2.org/downloads/gadget-server
                </a>
                and give
                it a try.
            </p>

            <h2>How to Run</h2>
            <ol>
                <li>Extract the downloaded zip</li>
                <li>Go to the bin directory in the extracted folder</li>
                <li>Run the wso2server.sh or wso2server.bat as appropriate</li>
                <li>Point your browser to the URL https://localhost:8443/carbon</li>
                <li>Use "admin", "admin" as the username and password to login as an admin
                    and create a user account
                </li>

                <li>Assign the required permissions to the user through a role</li>
                <li>If you need to start the OSGi console with the server use the property
                    -DosgiConsole when starting the server. The INSTALL.txt file found on the
                    installation directory will give you a comprehensive set of options and
                    properties that can be passed into the startup script
                </li>
            </ol>

            <h2>Key Features of WSO2 Gadget Server</h2>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <strong>Enterprise class Portal interface</strong>
                    - Users get to organise gadgets in a familiar
                    portal interface. Sets of gadgets can be organised using tabs. Individual
                    gadgets can be moved between tabs as well as cloning an entire tab to be used as
                    the foundation for a new tab.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Client Side Gadgets</strong>
                    - Any gadget adhering to the Google Gadget Specification can
                    be added to the portal. These gadgets are basically HTML and Javascript embedded
                    in XML. They can be hosted in any publicly accessible Web Server. The URL of the
                    gadget XML is used to add them to the Portal.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Enterprise Gadget Repository</strong>
                    - Organisations can maintain a central repository
                    of gadgets. Portal users can browse and add gadgets from this repository to
                    their individual portals, while rating and commenting on individual gadgets.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Anonymous Mode</strong>
                    - Users can experience most of the Portal's functionality
                    'excluding' the gadget Repository even before registration and sign in. All data
                    in this mode will be stored in the user's browser.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>OAuth Support for Gadgets</strong>
                    - Gadget Server enables to add OAuth keys for gadgets
                    to communicate with external APIs such as Google GData, Twitter etc.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Inter-gadget Communication</strong>
                    - Gadget Server allows inter gadget communication.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>I18n Support for Gadget</strong>
                    - Gadget Server supports internationalization of gadgets.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>User registration, sign-in and external user stores</strong>
                    - User registration and sign
                    in can be done using OpenID or Infocards in addition to the traditional user
                    name and password based scheme. Also the Gadget can be integrated to a external
                    user stores such as LDAP and AD.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Management Console</strong>
                    - Helps configure and manage the server, its users and the
                    Enterprise Gadget Repository via an intuitive browser based administrative
                    interface.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Custom Layouts for Tabs</strong>
                    - Gadget Server users can choose a desired layout form six different layouts
                    when creating a new tab.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Role Based Permissions</strong>
                    - Gadgets can be restricted based on users role.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Make SOAP Request Support</strong>
                    - Not only REST style requests, gadgets written for WSO2 Gadget Server can
                    consume SOAP only web service via make SOAP Request.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Theming Support</strong>
                    - Gadget Server users can create custom templates for the portal UI, and add
                    them via Gadget Server management console.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Gadget Archive Deployment</strong>
                    - With WSO2 Carbon Application deployment, users can, write gadgets using
                    Carbon Studio and deploy the gadget archive in to the Gadget server.
                </li>
            </ul>

            <h2>New Features of the WSO2 Gadget Server 1.4.0</h2>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <strong>Based on Carbon 3.2.0</strong>
                    - Gadget Server release is based on Carbon "Middleware a' la carte" which is an
                    OSGi
                    based SOA platform version 3.2.0 by WSO2 Inc.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Optimized Performance</strong>
                    - Gadget Server users can now experience better performance in dashboard and
                    gadget loading due to asynchronous gadget rendering.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Search Enabled Gadget Repository</strong>
                    - Search enabled gadget repository now allow
                    users to search for gadgets inside gadget repository.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Improved UI to Pick Gadgets</strong>
                    - Gadget Server users can now pick gadget XML from registry,
                    File system or from external repositories.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Enhanced Permission Model for Theming</strong>
                    - Now gadget server supports new permission model for
                    theming usage where the administrator could set permission
                    for different users to use different themes.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Improved Gadget Source Editor</strong>
                    - Now users can edit gadget source at the gadget
                    repository itself using the user friendly gadget source editor.
                </li>
            </ul>
		
	   <h2>
                Issues Fixed in This Release
            </h2>
            <ul> <li><a href="https://wso2.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?mode=hide&amp;requestId=10543">WSO2
				Gadget Server</a></li> 
					<li><a href="https://wso2.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?mode=hide&amp;requestId=10546">Gadget Server
				Components of the WSO2 Carbon Platform</a></li> 
				</ul>
		<h2>Known Issues</h2> 
 
				<ul> 
					<li><a href="https://wso2.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?mode=hide&amp;requestId=10544">WSO2
				Gadget Server</a></li> 
					<li><a href="https://wso2.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?mode=hide&amp;requestId=10545">Gadget Server
				Components of the WSO2 Carbon Platform</a></li> 
				</ul> 
	
            <h2>How You Can Contribute</h2>
            <h3>
                Mailing Lists
            </h3>
            <p>
                Join our mailing list and correspond with the developers directly.
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Developer List :
                    <a href="mailto:carbon-dev@wso2.org">carbon-dev@wso2.org</a>
                    |
                    <a href="mailto:carbon-dev@wso2.org-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">
                        Subscribe
                    </a>
                    |
                    <a href="http://www.wso2.org/mailarchive/carbon-dev/">Mail Archive</a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    User List :
                    <a href="mailto:gs-user@wso2.org">gs-user@wso2.org</a>
                    |
                    <a href="mailto:gs-user-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">Subscribe</a>
                    |
                    <a href="http://www.wso2.org/mailarchive/gs-user/">Mail Archive</a>
                </li>
            </ul>

            <h3>
                Reporting Issues
            </h3>
            <p>
                WSO2 encourages you to report issues and your enhancement requests for the
                WSO2 Gadget Server using the public<a
                    href="https://wso2.org/jira/browse/GS">JIRA</a>.
            </p>
            <p>
                You can also watch how they are resolved, and comment on the progress..
            </p>
            <h3>
                Discussion Forums
            </h3>
            <p>
                Alternatively, questions could be raised using the forums available.
            </p>
            <p>
                <a href="http://wso2.org/forum/966">WSO2 Gadget Server Forum</a>
                :
                Discussion forum for WSO2 Gadget Server developers/users
            </p>
            

            <h2>Support</h2>
            <p>WSO2 Inc. offers a variety of development and production support
                programs, ranging from Web-based support up through normal business
                hours, to premium 24x7 phone support.
            </p>

            <p>For additional support information please refer to
                <a href="http://wso2.com/support/">http://wso2.com/support/</a>
            </p>

            <p>For more information on WSO2 Gadget Server, visit the WSO2 Oxygen Tank
                (<a href="http://wso2.org">http://wso2.org</a>)
            </p>

            <p>We welcome your feedback on this implementation. Thank you for your interest in WSO2
                Gadget Server.
            </p>
            <br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve"/>
            <br xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:space="preserve"/>
            <br></br>
            <p>
                <i>-- The WSO2 Gadget Server Team --</i>
            </p>
        </div>
        <script language="javascript">
            dp.SyntaxHighlighter.BloggerMode();
            dp.SyntaxHighlighter.HighlightAll('code');
        </script>
    </body>
</html>
