<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!--
  ~  Copyright (c) 2011, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
  ~
  ~  WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
  ~  Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
  ~  in compliance with the License.
  ~  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  ~  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  ~  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  ~  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  ~  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  ~  under the License.
  -->

<!DOCTYPE html
     PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"
     "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en">
  <head>
      <meta content="text/html; charset=iso-8859-1" http-equiv="content-type"/>
      <title>WSO2 LB v1.0.0 Released - 28th Oct. 2011</title>
  </head>
  <body>
  <div id="header">
</div>

<div id="main-content">
<h1>The WSO2 Load Balancer (LB) 1.0.0 Released!</h1>

<p>
    The WSO2 LB team is pleased to announce the release of version 1.0.0 of
    the Open Source Load Balancer (LB).
</p>

<p>
    WSO2 LB is a fast, lightweight and user friendly open source Load Balancer (LB)
    distributed under the <a href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0.html">Apache
    Software License v2.0</a>. WSO2 LB allows system administrators and developers to
    easily configure fail over routing, load balancing, service aware load balancing, 
    and dynamic load balancing with auto scaling.The LB runtime is designed to be 
    completely asynchronous, non-blocking and streaming based on the 
    <a href="http://synapse.apache.org">Apache Synapse</a> mediation engine.
</p>

<p>
    WSO2 LB 1.0.0 is developed on top of the revolutionary
    <a href="http://wso2.org/projects/carbon">WSO2 Carbon platform</a> (Middleware a' la carte),
    an OSGi based framework that provides seamless modularity to your SOA via
    componentization. This release also contains many new features and a range of optional
    components (add-ons) that can be installed to customize the behavior of the LB. Further, any
    existing features of the LB which are not required to your environment can be easily
    removed using the underlying provisioning framework of Carbon. In brief, WSO2 LB can
    be fully customized and tailored to meet your exact SOA needs.
</p>

<p>
    You can download this distribution from <a href="http://wso2.org/downloads/lb">
    http://wso2.org/downloads/lb</a> and give it a try.</p>

<h2>How to Run </h2>
<ol>
  <li>Extract the downloaded zip</li>
  <li>Go to the bin directory in the extracted folder</li>
  <li>Run the wso2server.sh or wso2server.bat as appropriate</li>
  <li>Configure the load balancer to manage the load across the instants to be balanced.</li>
  <li>If you need to start the OSGi console with the server use the property
    -DosgiConsole when starting the server. The INSTALL.txt file found on the
    installation directory will give you a comprehensive set of options and
    properties that can be passed into the startup script</li>
</ol>

<h2>Key Features of WSO2 LB</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Non-blocking HTTP/S transports based on Apache HttpCore-NIO for ultra-fast
   execution and support for thousands of connections at high concurrency with
   constant memory usage.</li>
  <li>Built in support for scheduling tasks using the Quartz scheduler.</li>
  <li>Load-balancing (with or without sticky sessions)/Fail-over, and clustered
   Throttling and Caching support</li>
  <li>Lightweight, XML and Web services centric messaging model</li>
  <li>Automatically scaling the system according to the load across the nodes in
   the service nodes that are in the cluster.
  </li>
  <li>Service aware dynamic load balancing - A single load balancer
   can centrally manage the load across the nodes of different service clusters.
  </li>
</ul>

<h2>How You Can Contribute</h2>
    <h3>
      Mailing Lists
    </h3>
    <p>
      Join our mailing list and correspond with the developers directly.
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        Developer List : <a href="mailto:carbon-dev@wso2.org">carbon-dev@wso2.org</a>
        | <a href="mailto:carbon-dev-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">Subscribe</a>
        | <a href="http://wso2.org/mailarchive/carbon-dev/">Mail Archive</a>
      </li>
      <li>
        User List : <a href="mailto:lb-user@wso2.org">lb-java-user@wso2.org</a>
        | <a href="mailto:lb-user-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">Subscribe</a>
        | <a href="http://wso2.org/mailarchive/lb-user/">Mail Archive</a>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <h3>
      Reporting Issues
    </h3>
    <p>
      We encourage you to report issues, documentation faults and feature requests regarding
      WSO2 LB through the public <a href="http://www.wso2.org/jira/browse/lb">LB JIRA</a>. You
      can use the <a href="http://www.wso2.org/jira/browse/CARBON">Carbon JIRA</a> to report any
      issues related to the Carbon base framework or associated Carbon components.
    </p>

    <h3>
      Discussion Forums
    </h3>
    <p>
      Alternatively, questions could be raised using the forums available.
    </p>
    <p>
      <a href="http://wso2.org/forum/1261">WSO2 LB Forum</a> :
      Discussion forum for WSO2 LB developers/users
    </p>

<h2>Support</h2>
<p>
    We are committed to ensuring that your enterprise middleware deployment is
    completely supported from evaluation to production. Our unique approach
    ensures that all support leverages our open development methodology and is
    provided by the very same engineers who build the technology.
</p>
<p>
    For more details and to take advantage of this unique opportunity please
    visit <a href="http://wso2.com/support">http://wso2.com/support</a>.
</p>


<p><i>-- The WSO2 LB Team --</i> </p>
</div>
  </body>
</html>
