<!--
~ Copyright 2005-2008 WSO2, Inc. (http://wso2.com)
~
~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
~
~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
~
~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
~ limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <body>
	<p>[<a
                href="http://wso2.org/downloads/mashup">Download</a>]
            | [<a href="index_docs.html">Documentation Home</a>] | [<a
                    href="release_notes.html">Release Note</a>]
        </p>
        <div id="main-content">

            <h1>The Mashup Server Web Console</h1>


            <p>This document describes the WSO2 Mashup Server Web Console, which
                is accessible through
                <a href="https://localhost:9443/carbon">https://localhost:9443/carbon</a>
                in a vanilla installation.
                The Web Console helps the user to
                perform several tasks based on the
                permissions he is given. The default permissions allow annonymous users
                to search, view and tryit all mashups. Users who are logged
                in can perform administrative tasks associated
                with creating and managing mashups.
            </p>

            <p>
                <img alt="mashup ui" src="images/mashup-ui.png"/>
            </p>


            <p>The above shows the service listing of a vanilla installation (Once you've
                logged in, go to <strong>Manage > Services > List</strong>). It shows all available mashups together with links to WSDL
                1.1, WSDL 2.0 and Try this service operation.
            </p>

            <h2>Mashup Page</h2>
            <p>
                The mashup/service page lists all resources associated with a mashup. It gives
                links to all resources that are associated with that mashup and also
                helps manage and edit the mashup.
            </p>
            <p>
                The following resources of a mashup can be accessed from this page.
            </p>

            <ol>
                <li><strong>Quality of Service configuration</strong></li>
                <ul>
                    <li>Security</li>
                    <li>Policies</li>
                    <li>Reliable Messaging</li>
                    <li>Transports</li>
                    <li>Response Caching</li>
                    <li>Modules</li>
                    <li>Access Throttling</li>
                    <li>Operations</li>
                    <li>MTOM</li>
                    <li>Parameters</li>
                </ul>
                <li><strong>Edit Mashup</strong>: Users can edit their services source, custom UI and gadget code.
                </li>
                <li><strong>API Documentation</strong>: Displays the API Documentation for the service.
                </li>
                <li><strong>Custom UI</strong>: If the service has a custom UI, then this link will be pointed to that.
                    Otherwise the user will be
                    redirected to the tryit page of the service.
                </li>
                <li><strong>Source Code</strong>: Source code for this service.
                </li>
                <li><strong>XML Schema</strong>: Schema definition for the service.
                </li>
                <li><strong>Javascript(DOM) Stub</strong>: Javascript DOM stub, which is to be used under browser
                    environment.
                </li>
                <li><strong>Javascript(E4X) Stub</strong>: Javascript E4X stub, which is to be used to access a servie
                    from
                    a service.
                </li>
                <li><strong>Javascript(E4X) Stub [localhost endpoints]</strong>: Javascript E4X stub with localhost
                    endpoints,
                    which is to be used to access a local service from a service.
                </li>
            </ol>
            <p>
                <img alt="mashup meta-data" src="images/mashup.png"/>
            </p>

            <h2><a id="creating_new_mashup"/>Creating a New Mashup
            </h2>


            <p>
                The Web Console is capable of generating a skeleton Javascript
                service and a skeleton Custom UI for
                the user (A user should be logged in to perform this operation). Click the
                <strong>Create</strong>
                link which is located in the <strong>Manage > Services > Add > JavaScript Service > Create</strong>. When you
                enter a
                name for the new service, you will be taken to the
                <a href="#editing_mashups">edit mashup</a>
                window. There you can do the necessary editing and save or cancel the
                changes depending on your preference. The new mashup will be listed as
                a service in a few seconds.
            </p>
            <br/>
            <p>
                <img alt="mashup meta-data" src="images/mashup.png"/>

            </p>
            <h2><a id="editing_mashups"/>Editing Mashups
            </h2>


            <p>The Mashup Editor allows you to edit the source code, the Custom
                UI and the Google gadget of your Services and Mashups. You can launch
                the editor from service dashboard ("Edit Mashup" link under Specific Configuration listing). Once you
                have
                completed editing the service, you can Apply the changes (Saves the
                mashup and keeps you on the editor page), Save Changes (Takes you to
                the Service Listing page) or Discard the changes (No Mashup is created or changes will not be applied).
                The
                editor can also generate a Custom UI or a Google gadget skeleton for
                your mashup. This will serve as an easy starting point when developing
                a user interface for your mashup.
            </p>
            <br/>
            <p>
                <img alt="editing source" src="images/mash_editor_hellow.png"/>
            </p>
            <br/>
            <p>You can also use the editor to edit your custom UI and to generate a skeleton Google gadget.</p>

        </div>
    </body>
</html>
