<!--
~ Copyright 2005-2008 WSO2, Inc. (http://wso2.com)
~
~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
~
~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
~
~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
~ limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

    <body>
	<p>[<a
                href="http://wso2.org/downloads/mashup">Download</a>]
            | [<a href="index_docs.html">Documentation Home</a>] | [<a
                    href="release_notes.html">Release Note</a>]
        </p>

        <div id="main-content">
            <h1>Welcome to the WSO2 Mashup Server @mashup_version@</h1>
            <p>This document provides an
                introduction to the concepts and use of the Mashup Server, and will help you
                get started using Web service technology.
            </p>

            <h2>Web Services and Mashups</h2>
            <p>Mashups are becoming an increasingly important part of the information age.
                They allow you to tame the raging information flow and put it work for
                you. Rather than being forced to consume information in the way the publisher
                wishes it presented, increasingly users are finding the power to consume raw
                information, combine it with other data sources, customize and shape the
                results, and interact with that information. Getting information in the way
                you want it is the basis of XML-based Web Services.
            </p>

            <p>XML is a language for exchanging information. It extends the valuable
                characteristics of HTML, which is limited to the domain of document
                publishing, to other fields. It allows one to use vocabularies specific to
                the information domain of the data. For instance, HTML has document-oriented
                concepts such as 'paragraph' and 'table', but no concept of 'price' or
                'temperature'. XML allows you to define your own data vocabulary. With XML,
                the presentation of the information can be separated from the content of the
                information - the first step in making that information reusable by the
                consumer.
            </p>

            <p>But if anyone can make up their own language, isn't that the Tower of Babel
                all over again? Indeed, to communicate effectively, two computers must agree
                on the data format (with XML this is easy since it's virtually universally
                accepted as a standard format), and on the vocabulary. Vertical industries
                and communities have evolved vocabularies that allow them to communicate
                within their domains. For instance, the HTML community can talk together in
                XML by using the XHTML vocabulary (HTML reformulated in XML). Bloggers can
                talk together in XML by using the RSS or Atom vocabularies. Thousands of
                formats have emerged to enable eBusiness transactions. But there still is a
                need for some human intervention to take disparate vocabularies and combine
                them into a new information stream.
            </p>

            <p>Merging, or mashing-up data, thus is a process of acquiring XML (directly
                from the producers, or in some other legacy form that can be converted to
                XML), processing and combining that data, and publishing the results. If the
                result of the mashup is expressed as new XML data, it can again be shared
                with others, further mashed, and presented to the user in a variety of ways
                (including but not limited to HTML). The WSO2 Mashup Server is based on this
                model - that the central model for customizing information to a particular
                user's needs, is one of consuming, processing, and publishing XML.
            </p>

            <p>How does one acquire XML? Web Services are a set of technologies that helps
                get XML from one place to another, providing protocols for describing what
                XML is available, how to ask for it, how to transmit the data securely,
                reliably, and so forth. From the perspective of the Mashup author, the less
                one has to know about the details of how the XML gets from one place to
                another, the better. The core functionality of the Mashup Server is to take
                care of this for you, allowing you to operate at the level of the XML content
                itself as much as possible.
            </p>

            <p>Mashup products and frameworks all have several pieces in common. They
                provide ways to acquire data, they provide a central abstraction and tools
                for working with that data, and they provide ways to publish the result to
                the consumer. The WSO2 Mashup Server uses Web Services as the mechanism for
                acquiring data, XML as its central abstraction, Javascript (with E4X XML
                extensions) for manipulating that data, and again Web Services as the primary
                way to re-publish the new information stream, with bridges to HTML, RSS, and
                other output mechanisms.
            </p>

            <p>In this User Guide, you will learn how to acquire, manipulate and publish XML
                data through Web Services, and how to build upon that foundation to create
                sophisticated distributed applications simply and rapidly.
            </p>


            <h2>WSO2 Mashup Server @mashup_version@ Release</h2>

            <p>
                The @mashup_version@ release of the WSO2 Mashup Server is mainly forcused on providing OSGi based WSO2 Carbon Platform support.
                Hence it is now based on award winning WSO2 Carbon Platform where users can add remove components with an ease.
                This is a unification of all Java based products from WSO2. Now you can have features from the lighweight superfast WSO2 ESB &amp;
                the WSAS running on your Mashup Server instance. Enhanced admin UI, extensible server admin framework, separable frontend &amp; backend
                where a single frontend server can be used to administer several backend servers and clustering are major features inherited from
                WSO2 Carbon Platform. It also have made enhancements for the former release, where sevaral featurs have added to enhace your
                experience in authoring services.
            </p>

                <p>
                    Please refer to the
                    <a href="release_notes.html">Mashup Server @mashup_version@ Release Note</a>
                    for more details.
                </p>
            <h2>Mailling Lists</h2>
            <p>Your feedback on WSO2 Mashup Server is most appreciated. Please send them to our user mailing lists.</p> 
            <ul>
              <li>WSO2 Mashup Server Users' mailing list: <a href="mailto:mashup-user@wso2.org ">mashup-user@wso2.org </a> | <a href="mailto:mashup-user-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">Subscribe</a>
                | <a href="mailto:mashup-user-request@lists.wso2.com?subject=unsubscribe">Unsubscribe</a>
                | <a href="http://www.wso2.org/mailarchive/mashup-user/">Mail
                Archive</a></li>
            </ul>

            <ul>
              <li>WSO2 Mashup Server Developers' mailing list<a href="mailto:mashup-dev@wso2.org ">mashup-dev@wso2.org </a> | <a href="mailto:mashup-dev-request@wso2.org?subject=subscribe">Subscribe</a>
                | <a href="mailto:mashup-user-request@wso2.org?subject=unsubscribe">Unsubscribe</a>
                | <a href="http://www.wso2.org/mailarchive/mashup-dev/">Mail
                Archive</a></li>
            </ul>
        </div>
    </body>
</html>
