<!--
~ Copyright 2005-2008 WSO2, Inc. (http://wso2.com)
~
~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
~
~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
~
~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
~ limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
    <link href="css/mashup-docs.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all"/>
</head>
<body>

<div id="main-content">
<h1>Creating a Data Service using an RDBMS Data Source</h1>

<p>This document describes the steps to be followed when using the Data
Service Creation Wizard with an RDBMS data source.</p>
<br/>


<h2>Step 1</h2>

<p>In the Configuration box, enter a name for the new Data Service and from
the Data Source dropdown, select RDBMS. A popup window will open up. Here,
enter database connection details including driver class, JDBC URL, username
and password. The JDBC driver should be available in the MASHUP_HOME/lib
directory. </p>

<p><img alt="DS RDBMS Step 1" src="images/ds_rdbms_step1.png" width="1049"
height="482"/></p>

<p>After entering details, you can click on Test Connection to see whether
the connection is functional. If the connection tests succeeds, you will see
the dialog below.</p>

<p><img alt="Testing Connection" src="images/ds_rdbms_step1_test.png"
width="369" height="147"/></p>

<p>Click OK, to confirm the connection details and click next.</p>
<br/>


<h2>Step 2</h2>

<p>Click on New Query to create a new query for you data service. You will be
presented with the Add New Query popup window.</p>

<p><img alt="DS RDBMS Step 2" src="images/ds_rdbms_step2.png" width="1012"
height="703"/></p>
<br/>


<h2>Step 3</h2>

<p>Click the Add New Output Mapping button to define mappings for the query
output.</p>

<p><img alt="Step 3 - Output Mapping" src="images/ds_rdbms_step3.png"
width="619" height="284"/></p>

<p>Click OK on the popup windows to go back to the Queries panel. Click Next.
</p>
<br/>


<h2>Step 4</h2>

<p>In the next panel, click on Add New Operation to define operations for the
data service. </p>

<p><img alt="Add Operation" src="images/ds_rdbms_step4.png" width="1007"
height="635"/></p>

<p>In the popup window, the Query dropdown will list the queries you defined
in the previous step. You can map them to operations here. Click Finish when
done.</p>

<p><img alt="Finish" src="images/ds_rdbms_step5.png" width="1004"
height="737"/></p>
<br/>


<h2>Step 5</h2>

<p>Your new data service will now be included in the list of Mashups on your
server.</p>

<p><img alt="Listing" src="images/ds_rdbms_step5_list.png" width="705"
height="85"/></p>

<p>You can access the mashup page for this service and use
<strong>tryIt</strong> to try the operation you defined.</p>

<p><img alt="Result" src="images/ds_rdbms_step6.png" width="993"
height="785"/></p>
</div>
</body>
</html>
