<!--
~ Copyright 2005-2008 WSO2, Inc. (http://wso2.com)
~
~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
~
~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
~
~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
~ limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
    <link href="css/mashup-docs.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all"/>
</head>
<body>
	<p>[<a
                href="http://wso2.org/downloads/mashup">Download</a>]
            | [<a href="index_docs.html">Documentation Home</a>] | [<a
                    href="release_notes.html">Release Note</a>]
        </p>
<div id="main-content">
    <h1>Securing Mashups</h1>

    <p>The Mashup Server allows users to secure their mashups using
        WS-Security. All the complexities of WS-Security are hidden under the
        covers so that users can apply security scenarios of their mashups with
        ease. Once a security scenario is applied the corresponding WSDL of that
        mashup will display the WS-Security policy that has been engaged on that mashup.
        Hence consumers of this mashup will be able to consume your secured
        mashup by processing the information available in the WSDL.</p>

    <p>Securing
        mashups deployed on the Mashup Server can be done by visiting the dashboard of the mashup service. There is a link named "Security"
        under "Quality of Service Configuration" section on the service dashboard. When you use WSO2 Mashup Server in production, 
        it is strongly recommended that you change the default keys that are shipped with it.
        Please refer the <a
            href="keys.html">Changing Keys</a> section for setting up private keys.</p>

    <h2 id="managing">Applying Security Scenarios</h2>

    <p>The Security Scenarios page lists the security scenarios that can be
        applied to a mashup. The Mashup Server ships with 15 most commonly used
        security scenarios which can be applied into a mashup by
        selecting the desired scenario and clicking "Next". By default any
        mashup is unsecured.</p>

    <p><img
        src="images/configure_security.png" alt="Configure Security"/></p>

    <p>Some of the security scenarios listed above will require the user to specify
    the users and roles that are authorized to access the service. These are the
    security scenarios that involve Username Token Authentication. When
    such a scenario is applied you will be prompt with a list of
    available users and roles.</p>

    <p><img src="images/assign_users_and_roles.png" style="width: 1003px;"
                                                            alt="Assign Users and Roles"/></p>

    <p>Providing
    access to the "admin" role would mean that any user in
    the Mashup Server registered under admin user group will be able to access this service. </p>

    <p><strong>NOTE: </strong>The generated stub provides facilities to access mashups secured using
    "UsernameToken" while the <a href="wsrequesthostobject.html">WSRequest host object</a>
    provides facilities to access any secured mashup.</p>
</div>

</body>
</html>
