<!--
  ~ Copyright 2005-2007 WSO2, Inc. (http://wso2.com)
  ~
  ~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  ~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  ~ limitations under the License.
  -->

<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
        "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <body>
        <p>[<a
                href="http://dist.wso2.org/products/mashup/2.3.0/wso2ms-2.3.0.zip">Download</a>]
            | [<a href="index_docs.html">Documentation Index</a>] | [<a
                    href="release_notes.html">Release Note</a>]
        </p>

        <h1>User Guide</h1>

        <p>This document provides information and instructions on the functionality
            of WSO2 Mashup Server. Your feedback on WSO2 Mashup Server is most appreciated. Please send them to our <a
                    href="mail-lists.html">mailing lists</a>.
        </p>
        <a name="introduction"/>
        <h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

        <p>The WSO2 Mashup Server allows you to acquire web based information from a
            variety of sources such as Web services, Web pages, Databases or Feeds,
            combine it in interesting and useful ways before exposing the result
            again as a Web service or page, Feed or a Google gadget. If you still haven't
            installed Mashup Server, please take a look at the
            <a href="installation_guide.html">installation guide.</a>
        </p>


        <p>The functionality of the Management Console is described below in detail.</p>
        <a name="welcome"/>
        <h2 id="welcome">Welcome Page</h2>

        <p>Once WSO2 Mashup Server has been successfully installed (see
            <a href="installation_guide.html">Installation Guide</a>
            for installation
            details), start the WSO2 Mashup Server. Then, launch a Web browser instance and
            point it to the URL
            <a href="https://localhost:9443/carbon/">https://localhost:9443/carbon/</a>
            if you are using the default settings.
            This will take you to the welcome page of the WSO2 Mashup Server Console.
            <strong>Note</strong>:
            WSO2 Mashup Server has two transport listeners: HTTP and
            HTTPS. By default, the HTTP listener opens on port 9763, while the HTTPS
            listener opens on port 9443. The administrator functionality is exposed only
            via the HTTPS port.
        </p>
        <p>
            <img src="images/provisioning.png" alt=""/>
        </p>
        <a name="signin"/>
        <h2 id="signin">Signing In</h2>

        <p>Signing in will be available in the upper right hand corner.
            When the user clicks the "sign in" link, it will automatically redirect
            the request to secure protocol httpss, if user has already in http protocol. Once the
            correct credentials are provided, the user will be logged in to the Mashup Server Management Console.
        </p>

        <p>The default username and password to sign into WSO2 Mashup Server Management
            Console:
        </p>

        <p>
            <strong>User name :</strong>
            admin
            <br/>
            <strong>Password :</strong>
            admin
        </p>

        <p>
            The management console can point to different Mashup Server nodes in a production system. This can
            be done using the "Server URL" entry on the Sign In box.
            To solve any problems with signing in, click "Sign-in Help"
        </p>
        <a name="home"/>
        <h2 id="home">Home</h2>
        <p>The Home Page of the Management Console contain gadgets which are used to display the system summary.</p>
        <p>
            <img src="images/home.png" alt=""/>
        </p>

        <a name="manage"/>
        <h2 id="manage">Manage Services</h2>

        <p>As shown below, this page lists the available services or those deployed
            in each service group in the system, along with links to view the WSDLs of each service.
        </p>
        <p>
            <img src="images/mashup-ui.png" alt=""/>
        </p>

        <a name="remove"/>
        <h3 id="remove">Remove Service Group</h3>

        <p>A service group can be removed using the 'Remove' action
            icon listed for each service group, in which case all the services in that
            particular service archive will be removed from the system.
        </p>

        <a name="faulty"/>
        <h2 id="faulty">Faulty Services</h2>
        <p>
            <img src="images/faulty-services1.png" alt=""/>
        </p>

        <a name="deleting"/>
        <h3 id="deleting">Deleting Faulty Services:</h3>

        <p>If a
            <strong>faulty service</strong>
            is deployed, it will be displayed on
            the Available Services page as
            <strong>[n] Faulty
                Service Group(s)
            </strong>
        </p>

        <p>Clicking on the faulty service link will open the faulty services page, on
            which the details of the faulty services will be listed. On this page,
            you will be able to delete the faulty service.
        </p>

        <a name="service1"/>
        <h3 id="service1">Service Group Management</h3>
        <p>
            <img src="images/service-groups.png" alt=""/>
        </p>
        <p>

            Clicking on the Service Group on the main page of Manage Services,
            will open a page on which you can:
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li><strong>Manage Service Group Parameters</strong>: Users can add, update or delete parameters from the
                admin console. Parameters should be given a name and a value, which consist of well formatted XML.
            </li>
            <li><strong>Manage Module Engagements</strong>: Lists the modules engaged
                at the service group level and on a global level. You can also engage or
                disengage modules to the specific service group.
            </li>
            <li><strong>Create Service Archive</strong>: This feature will provide the user to create an Axis2 archive
                out of all the configurations available to a given service group. Thus, before shipping the service to a
                production environment, users can test whether all related functions such as parameters, module
                engagement, polices etc are available or its validity &amp; so on. Though this will give tremendous
                development time feature, it has its limitations. Currently this feature could archive a created or
                generated .AAR. Mashup Server distribution comes with data services, pojo services, and Axis1 services
                support. All these domains do not have archives. They would simply be a file with XML formatted
                description. Thus, if such a service is tried to be archived, Mashup Server would not allow it. It
                should be noted that an archive can be created only for a service group, not to an individual service.
                Service group is mapped to a physical .AAR. Thus, it's logical to create an archive only to a service
                group instead.
            </li>
            <li><strong>MTOM Configuration</strong>: MTOM is allowed to be configured in three ways, True, False and
                Optional. If one of these values are changed, this will cause all underline services and operations to
                change its way of corresponding to MTOM
            </li>
        </ul>

        <a name="service2"/>
        <h3 id="service2">Service Management</h3>

        <p>Clicking on the service of a specific service group on the main page of
            "<a href="#manage">Manage Services</a>", will show the Service Dashboard that contains certain
            <strong>service specific information</strong>
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li><strong>Edit Mashup</strong>: Users can edit their services source, custom UI and gadget code.
            </li>
            <li><strong>API Documentation</strong>: Displays the API Documentation for the service.
            </li>
            <li><strong>Custom UI</strong>: If the service has a custom UI, then this link will be pointed to that.
                Otherwise the user will be
                redirected to the tryit page of the service.
            </li>
            <li><strong>Source Code</strong>: Source code for this service.
            </li>
            <li><strong>XML Schema</strong>: Schema definition for the service.
            </li>
            <li><strong>Javascript(DOM) Stub</strong>: Javascript DOM stub, which is to be used under browser
                environment.
            </li>
            <li><strong>Javascript(E4X) Stub</strong>: Javascript E4X stub, which is to be used to access a servie from
                a service.
            </li>
            <li><strong>Javascript(E4X) Stub [localhost endpoints]</strong>: Javascript E4X stub with localhost
                endpoints,
                which is to be used to access a local service from a service.
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>
            <img src="images/mashup.png" border="1" alt=""/>
        </p>

        <a name="securring"/>
        <h3>Securing a Service</h3>
        <p>
            The following image shows the options available for securing a service by applying security scenarios.
        </p>
        <p>
            <img src="images/configure_security.png" border="1" alt=""/>
        </p>
	    <p><br/></p>
        <p>
            For more details see
            <a href="securityconfig/docs/userguide.html">here</a>
        </p>

        <a name="throttling"/>
        <h3>Access Throttling</h3>
        <p>
            Access throttling configuration for the HelloService is shown below.
        </p>
        <p>
            <img src="images/throttling.png" border="1" alt=""/>
        </p>
        <p><br/></p>
        <p>
            For more details see
            <a href="throttling/docs/userguide.html">here</a>
        </p>

        <a name="caching"/>
        <h3>Response Caching</h3>
        <p>
            Response caching configuration for the HelloService is shown below.
        </p>
        <p>
            <img src="images/caching.png" border="1" alt=""/>
        </p>
        <p></p>
        <p>
            For more details see
            <a href="caching/docs/userguide.html">here</a>
        </p>

        <a name="rm"/>
        <h3>Reliable Messaging</h3>
        <p>
            Reliable Messaging Configuration for the HelloService is shown below.
        </p>
        <p>
            <img src="images/rm.png" border="1" alt=""/>
        </p>

        <p>
            For more details see
            <a href="rm/docs/userguide.html">here</a>
        </p>

        <a name="policies"/>
        <h3>Edit Policies</h3>
        <p>
            Policy editing options for the HelloService is shown below.
        </p>
        <p>
            <img src="images/policy.png" border="1" alt=""/>
        </p>

        <p>
            For more details see
            <a href="policyeditor/docs/userguide.html">here</a>
        </p>
    </body>
</html>

