<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!--
  ~  Copyright (c) 2005-2008, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
  ~
  ~  WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
  ~  Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
  ~  in compliance with the License.
  ~  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  ~  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  ~  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  ~  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  ~  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  ~  under the License.
  ~
  -->

<!DOCTYPE html
   PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
   "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd" >

<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
<title> WSO2 Governance Registry - User Guide </title>
<link href="../css/greg-docs.css" rel="stylesheet"/>
<link href="../styles/dist-docs.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all"/>
</head>
<body>
[ <a href="../docs_index.html"> Documentation Index </a> ]
<h1> WSO2 Governance Registry - User Guide </h1>

<h2 id="governance_dashboard">Governance Dashboard</h2>    
<p>
The Governance Dashboard consists of a number of gadgets that provides a visual representation of various data present in the WSO2 Governance Registry.
</p>
<p>
The functionality of each of these gadgets will be illustrated below under different sections.
</p>
<h3>The Impact Analysis Gadget</h3>

<p>This gadget gives an impact analysis of various artifacts associated with web services. An overview of the associated schemas, WSDLs and policies are shown for each service. If a WSDL has associated schemas/policies, these dependencies are also shown in this gadget.</p>

<p>The drop down list allows you to select any of the services present in the Governance Registry. When a service is selected all associated artifacts are displayed in a dependency tree. A click on any of the nodes on the tree opens the relevant resource.
<br/>
<br/>
<img src="../images/gadgets-impact-analysis.png" alt="Impact Analysis Gadget"/>
<br/>
<br/>
</p>

<h3>The Resource Impact Gadget</h3>

<p>This gadget shows the impact which any resource has to any other resources. An overview of the relations and the related resources are shown for a resource. 
</p>
        <p>
            The text box allows you to enter a path of a resource. When the path is submitted, the respective associations and associated resources are shown as a dependency tree. A click on a respective node bring it into focus.
            <br/>
            <br/>
<img src="../images/gadgets-resource-impact.png" alt="Resource Impact Gadget"/>            
    <br/>
<br/>
        </p>
   
   
 <h3>The Lifecycle Stage Monitor Gadget</h3>
<p>The lifecycle gadget gives an accumulation of the number of services in each life cycle. A pie chart displays this through each life cycle.</p>

<p>The drop down list allows you to select any lifecycle which has been associated with at least one service resource on the registry. For each selection a chart is shown giving the number of services in each lifecycle.</p>
<br/>
<br/>
<img src="../images/gadgets-lifecycle-stage.png" alt="Lifecycle Stage Monitor Gadget"/>            

<br/>
<br/>
</body>

</html>
