<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!--
  ~  Copyright (c) 2005-2008, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
  ~
  ~  WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
  ~  Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
  ~  in compliance with the License.
  ~  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  ~  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  ~  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  ~  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  ~  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  ~  under the License.
  ~
  -->

<!DOCTYPE html
   PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
   "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd" >

<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <head>
    <meta http-equiv="content-type" content="text/html; charset=iso-8859-1"/>
    <title>
      WSO2 Governance Registry - Governance Artifacts
    </title>
    <link href="../css/greg-docs.css" rel="stylesheet"/>
    <link href="../styles/dist-docs.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all"/>
  </head>
  <body xml:lang="en">
<h1>WSO2 Governance Registry - Governance Artifacts</h1>
<h2 id="metadata">Adding Governance Artifacts to Governance Registry</h2>
<p>
With Service Metadata you can import most of the information which is separately stored in the web in to the Governance Registry and manage them as Governance Registry Resources.  We provide users to add common service information through standard service metadata formats like using WSDL(Web  Services Description Language) files Policy file and schema files . User have to give the location of their WSDL, Policy or Schema files from local file system or as a URL, Governance Registry is importing those information in to Registry as resources. All the special resources are having their own Media Type which will be useful to users to handle them convenience way. 
</p>
<p>
All service metadata is going in to be in the directory governance based on the metadata type user is importing. As an example all the WSDLs are going to /_system/governance/wsdls/ , all the policies goes to /_system/governance/policies/ and all the schemas used to go to /governance/schemas/ directory. During the WSDL and Schema import we are providing WSDL validation(Not supporting WSDL2), WS-I Validation and Schema Validation. Please note that WSDL and Schema validation can optionally be disabled from the registry.xml.  Also, WSDL and Schema validation requires a connection to the internet for the very first time, and will not work on systems without internet connectivity. Instead of just storing the required artifact in to the repository we do some other tasks specific to the artifact type and those information is mentioned on following artifact type based descriptions.
</p>
<p>
With metadata management we are allowing users to manage the imported metadata as resources management in the Governance Registry since all the information are stored as resource information inside the Governance Registry. In the Metadata list part users can list imported Services, WSDLs, Schemas and Policies. For Service resources users can always update the information given and dependencies between service resources, Schemas and WSDLs can be viewed. If user add a given artifact in normal resource adding UI in Governance Registry, we perform the same process for each metadata type and create a symbolic link to the resource created in current location where you add the resource.
</p>
<h2 id="services-manage">Managing Services</h2>
<p>
Instead of using normal service metadata formats we are providing users to give their own service description through  add Service UI in the metadata sub menu. Users can provide their own name to the service and lot more information about the service which will be really useful when it comes to SOA Governance. In the Add service users can give state of the service which could be in Test stage, Deployed stage or in Deprecated stage and likewise user can provide information like Transport Protocols,Message Formats, Message Exchange Patterns etc. Add Service UI provide field to fill for WSDL URL and if user provide an actual WSDL URL given WSDL will import as the WSDL for the imported resource which create an Association between the imported service resource and imported WSDL. Meantime if user import a WSDL through Add WSDL UI we are creating a Service resource by available information from the WSDL, so user can go to service resource and add more service information by consuming edit service operation.
User can select a lifecycle for the given service from the current lifecycle list, and selected lifecycle will be added the resource and display in right panel. With Service media type resources users have to do lifecycle addition using service UI rather using right hand widget.
</p>
<h2 id="wsdl-manage">Managing WSDLs</h2>
<p>
Users can upload WSDL files from users local file system (as a <a href="resource_ui.html#creating-gar">Governance Archive</a>) or import from a given URL. During the importing WSDL is validating and put in to the registry. If the given WSDL is having any other WSDL imports those WSDLs also going through the same process and import in to the registry. All the schema/policy imports are also downloaded in to registry and put them in to the location where all the schemas/policies are stored. Instead of them WSDL can have number of endpoints and for the endpoints Registry is creating new resources and put them in to a general location where all the endpoints are saving. So single WSDL can have number of dependent resource at the end of import process and the WSDL resource will have associations and dependencies for those resources according to the relationship.

By default for all the WSDL imports Registry is creating Service Resource by default and add some of the useful data in to service resource by parsing the WSDL. Ex: Name, Namespace,WSDL URL (this is the location of WSDL stored in Registry), Endpoints if available in the WSDL.
</p>
<h2 id="schema-manage">Managing Schemas</h2>
<p>
Users can upload Schemas from users local file system (as a <a href="resource_ui.html#creating-gar">Governance Archive</a>) or import from a given URL. First schemas will be validated before storing to registry. During the schema import process original schema will be put in to the location where all the schemas are stored and if there are any other inner schema imports in the given schema those imports also put in to the registry through the same schema import process.
</p>
<h2 id="policy-manage">Managing Policies</h2>
<p>
Users can import Policies from users local file system or from a given URL. Given policy file will be added to the location to the place where all the policies are stored.
</p>
</body>
</html>
