<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!--
  ~  Copyright (c) 2005-2008, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
  ~
  ~  WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
  ~  Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
  ~  in compliance with the License.
  ~  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  ~  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  ~  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  ~  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  ~  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  ~  under the License.
  ~
  -->

<!DOCTYPE html
   PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
   "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd" >

<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
<title> WSO2 Governance Registry - User Guide </title>
<link href="../css/greg-docs.css" rel="stylesheet"/>
<link href="../styles/dist-docs.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all"/>
</head>
<body>
[ <a href="../docs_index.html"> Documentation Index </a> ]
<h1> WSO2 Governance Registry - User Guide </h1>

<h2 id="SymRemote">Symbolic links and Remote links</h2>
<p>
Symbolic links are much like hyperlinks to existing resources or collections in the local registry
instance. When you access a symbolic link, the actual resource meta-data, community features,
associations and the content can be viewed from that location. If you make a change to the Symlink
resource, the actual resource will get affected. These Symlink resources are soft links so that the
actual resource does not keep a count for links from which it is referenced by. Instead the link
shows a resource with a description saying that it couldn't make link to the original resource.
Symbolic and remote links doesn't support versioning at the moment.
</p>
<p>
Remote links are created to mount a collection of a remotely deployed registry instance to the local
instance. Any path/collection of the remote instance can be mounted at any point in the local
instance. After mounting, the rest is very similar to symbolic links. You can work on the remote
resource from the local instance.
</p>
<p>
Symbolic links and Remote links can be created in a similar way to adding a normal resource.
Create link "Method" drop down list contains options to add symbolic and remote links.
</p>

<img src="../resources/docs/images/add_symlink.png" width="492px"/>
<p>Figure 1 : Add Symbolic Link </p>

<p>When adding a symbolic link, you have to provide a name for the link and the path of an existing
resource or collection which is being linked. It creates a link to the particular resource.
The created symbolic link is shown by an icon with an arrow in the entries panel.</p>

<p><img src="../resources/docs/images/symlink.png" width="492px"/></p>
<p>Figure 2 : Symbolic Link</p>

<p>Adding a Remote link is much similar to adding a symbolic link. You can mount a collection in a
remotely deployed registry instance to your registry instance by adding a remote link. You can
provide a name for the remote link in the name field, and choose the instance to which you are going
to mount (Please refer the registry user guide to see how to configure the remote instances in
registry.xml). You can give the path of the remote collection which you need to mount for the path
field, or else the root collection will be mounted. </p>

<p><img src="../resources/docs/images/add_remotelink.png" width="492px"/></p>
<p>Figure 3 : Add Remote Link</p>

<p>After mounting the remote collection you can access and work on that collection from your local
instance.</p>



</body>

</html>
